——哦!——小心!
- Oh! - Watch it!
你想要什么，艾迪?
What's it to be, Eddie?
好消息还是坏消息?
Good news or bad?
噢!
Oh!
哦。
Oh.
——早,钱德勒。-早上好，哈里斯太太。
- Morning, Chandler. - Good morning, Mrs. Harris.
-你好吗?-今天是我的幸运日
- How are you? - It's my lucky day today.
每天都一样。
Same as every day.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
好吧。
All right.
为什么没人坐那个位子?
Why's no one took that seat?
也许我留着给你。
Maybe I saving it for you.
推了。
Shove over, then.
你不会相信的，维。
You won't believe this, Vi.
刚刚发生了一件最奇怪的事。
The strangest thing's just happened.
我想这是个征兆。
I reckon it's a sign.
艾达·哈里斯，为什么你的人不能像其他人一样担任这个职位?
Ada Harris, why that man of yours can't use the post like everybody else?
不是个好作家，我的艾迪。
Not much of a writer, my Eddie.
好冷。
Ooh! So cold.
——有人来吗?——没有。
- Anyone coming? - No.
——没有?——安全。
- No? - All clear.
哦，早上好，纽科姆先生。
Oh, morning, Mr. Newcombe.
一大早起床。
Up bright and early.
这是职责所在，哈里斯太太。
Duty calls, Mrs. Harris.
我侄女波西亚
Uh, my niece, Portia.
哦，很高兴，我肯定。
Oh, delighted, I'm sure.
——早。——早。
- Morning. - Morning.
彭罗斯小姐。
Ooh-ooh, Miss Penrose.
炸弹。
Bombs away.
你来的不是很早吗?
Aren't you awfully early?
已经1点半了，亲爱的。
It's gone half past 1:00, dear.
不。
No.
天啊，我的试镜。
Christ, my bloody audition.
哦，我没有衣服穿。
Oh, I haven't a thing to wear.
你穿什么都好看，亲爱的。
Oh, you look lovely in anything, dear.
在那里。
There.
这是什么?
What about this?
你把我的…脚本?
Oh, what have you done with my... script?
哦，等等，等等。坚持下去。
Oh, hang on, hang on. Hang on.
看在上帝的份上。
Oh, for God's sake.
在那里。亲爱的,祝你好运。
There. Good luck, sweetheart.
谢谢你,亲爱的。
Thanks, darling.
你是一个天使。
You're an angel.
没有你我该怎么办?
What would I do without you?
让我们玩得很开心!
Let's enjoy ourselves!
♬在靠近新奥尔良的路易斯安那州深处……♪
♪ Deep down in Louisiana close to New Orleans... ♪
这不是了不起的H太太和她值得信赖的伙伴吗。
Well, if it isn't the marvelous Mrs. H and her trusty sidekick.
女士们，你们要点什么?这是幸运的一周。
What can I get you, ladies? It's been a lucky week.
——哦。-两杯波特酒加柠檬。
- Oh. - Two port and lemon.
如果你是庄家，每周都很幸运。
Every week's lucky if you're the bookmaker.
你说的没错，亲爱的。
You're not wrong there, love.
请来两杯加柠檬的波尔图葡萄酒。
Two port and lemon, please.
当然，现在我有了你的公司，我很幸运。
Course, now I've got your company, I'm in clover.
阿奇先生，你以为喝一杯就能得到我们的陪伴吗?
You think you get our company for one drink, Mr. Archie?
这两个人是很会判断人的性格的。
Now, these two are a proper judge of character.
他们喜欢你，艾达·哈里斯。
They like you, Ada Harris.
如果他们这么聪明，为什么要跟着你?
Why they stick with you, if they're so smart?
她这么暴躁，你为什么还缠着她?
Why do you stick with her, her so crabby?
我第一次轮班时认识她的。
Met her me first shift building planes.
没有比他更好的朋友了。
Never had a better friend.
麻烦的是，她总是说真话。
Trouble with this one, she always speak the truth.
不能帮助自己。
Can't help herself.
这是一种可怕的折磨。
That is a terrible affliction.
好了，女士们，规矩点。
All right, behave yourself, ladies.
我会看着你的。
I'll be watching you.
战争已经持续了很长时间。
War's been over a long time.
你的埃迪再也不会回来了。
Your Eddie's never coming back.
继续。
Go on.
是的。
Yeah.
♪我有个女朋友，她看起来还好♪
♪ I got a gal, she looks just fine ♪
总要给我带威士忌和红酒
♪ Always bring me whiskey and wine ♪
♬早上吃早餐，晚上吃晚餐
♪ Breakfast in the morning and dinner at night ♪
♪她所做的一切，都恰到好处♪
♪ Everything she do, she do just right ♪
♬当我说:“你想做什么?”♪
♪ And when I say, "What you wanna do?" ♪
♬她说:“我只希望你做一件事。
♪ She said, "There's just one thing that I want from you" ♪
♪一点点摇摆，一点点滚动
♪ A little bit of rock, a little bit of roll ♪
♬♬有一点石头
♪ A little bit of rock ♪
♪哦，有点翻滚…♪
♪ Ooh, a little bit of roll... ♪
"亲爱的哈里斯太太，请查收随信附上的"爱德华·哈里斯中士的私人物品，"在波兰华沙附近的坠机现场找到的。
"Dear Mrs. Harris, "Please find enclosed the personal effects "of Sergeant Edward Harris, "recovered from a crash site near Warsaw, Poland.
"由于这一发现，"哈里斯中士现在被派往…“在行动中阵亡”，1944年3月2日。
"As a result of this discovery, "Sergeant Harris is now posted... "killed in action, "2 March 1944.
“请等待皇家空军中央管理局的进一步通知。”
"Please await further communication from RAF Central Administration."
哦,艾达。
Oh, Ada.
我很抱歉。
I'm so sorry.
我早该知道他…如果他可以的话，他会回我电话的，你知道……不管怎样。
I-I should've known he... He would've got back to me if he could've, you know... one way or another.
嗯…的,然后。
Well... that's that, then.
自由、无拘无束。
Footloose and fancy-free.
好吧,爱。
All right, love.
我希望它很快。
I hope it was quick.
想念你的。
Miss you.
不，晚上的派对，绝对可以，但婚礼早餐不行。
No, the evening do, absolutely, but not the wedding breakfast.
呃，你知道，夫人……哈里斯太太，打扰一下。可能你只是……把……-不，那是敲诈——哦。
Uh, you know, Mrs... Mrs. Harris, excuse me. Could you just... just take that... - No, that is extortion. - Oh.
你必须回去向他们解释，我们负担不起。
You must go back and explain to them that we can't possibly afford that.
那当然是香槟了。
Well, of course it must be champagne.
I-I-I……提醒他们查尔斯是他们的议员。
I-I-I... Remind them that Charles is their MP.
那一定很值钱吧?
That must be worth something, huh?
是的。
Yes.
Toodle-pip。
Toodle-pip.
这场婚礼会害死我的。
This wedding's going to be the death of me.
你有孩子吗，哈里斯太太?
Do you have children, Mrs. Harris?
从头到尾都是昂贵的噩梦。
A nightmare of expense from start to finish.
哦,是的。
Oh, yes.
可怜的唐太斯上将不得不做出最后的牺牲。
Poor old Admiral Dant had to make the ultimate sacrifice.
启航前往克里斯蒂和balmier海岸。
Setting sail for Christie's and balmier shores.
大家都说他是个可怕的人。
Dreadful man, by all accounts.
说到账目，唐太斯夫人，我想知道你能否把……我们已经勒紧裤腰带这么长时间了，我们还能呼吸真是个奇迹。
Talking of accounts, Lady Dant, I was wondering if you might be able to sett... We've been tightening our belts for so long now, it's a miracle we can all still breathe.
-这不是很神圣吗?——哦。
- Isn't it divine? - Oh.
我发誓我永远不会踏上蒙田大道，但是因为婚礼和“当我在巴黎”还有……我看到拉维桑特的那一刻…——Ravissante。-我被迷住了。
I swore I would never set foot in the Avenue Montaigne, but what with the wedding and "when in Paris" and... The moment I laid eyes on Ravissante... - Ravissante. - I was ravished.
总计500英镑。
To the tune of 500 pounds.
500英镑买条裙子?
500 quid for a dress?
嘘,嘘,嘘。上帝次煤。
Shh, shh, shh. Lord Dant.
我不介意承认最近的事情有点血腥，但是…当我戴上它的时候…没有什么比这个更重要。
I don't mind admitting things have been a bit bloody of late, but... when I put it on... nothing else matters.
乐天?
Lotte?
现在，快，把它藏起来。
Now, quickly, hide it away.
在我有时间对老爷动手之前不能让他看到。
His Lordship must not see it until I've had time to work on him.
哦。
Oh.
Ravissante.
克里斯汀•迪奥。
By Christian Dior.
晚安，亲爱的。
Night, love.
南伦敦邮报!
South London Post!
周六的结果!
Saturday results!
你所有的足球成绩。
All your football results.
——哦!-南伦敦邮报!
- Oh! - South London Post!
——对不起。——周六的结果!
- Sorry. - Saturday results!
你所有的足球成绩。
All your football results.
南伦敦邮报!
South London Post!
周六的结果!
Saturday results!
曼联2分，布莱克浦2分。
Manchester United two, Blackpool two.
纽卡斯尔五分，利物浦三分。
Newcastle five, Liverpool three.
普雷斯顿北端二分，朴茨茅斯二分。
Preston North End two, Portsmouth two.
现在我们回到剩余的体育报道。
And now we return to the rest of the sports report.
不!不!
No! No!
哦，是我的埃迪。
Oh, it's my Eddie.
这是我的天使。
It's my angel.
你对我这么简单，女人?
You gone simple on me, woman?
第六,我赢了。
I won, Vi.
我已经赢了。
I've won.
你想对她好点。
You want to make nice to her.
她只是去赢了赌局而已。
She's only gone and won the pools.
艾达，你打算怎么办?
Ada, what you going to do?
我要去买条裙子。
I'm going to buy a dress.
为军团之舞准备的漂亮东西。
Something pretty for the Legion Dance.
是的。
Yeah.
来自巴黎的克里斯汀·迪奥裙子。
A Christian Dior dress from Paris.
500英镑。
500 quid.
你赢了多少钱?
How much you win?
还有票吗?
Any more tickets, please?
女士,上哪儿去?
Where to, ma'am?
单身,紫小姐吗?
Single, Miss Violet?
嗯哼。不给我收拾男人的烂摊子。
Mm-hmm. No cleaning up after no man for me.
——啊。-早上好，纽康先生。
- Ah. - Morning, Mr. Newcombe.
哈里斯太太，我…我想你还没见过我侄女，萨曼莎。
Mrs. Harris, I, uh... I don't believe you've met my niece, Samantha.
哦，不，我还没有这个荣幸。
Oh, no, I haven't had the pleasure.
嗯,纽康比先生。
Um, Mr. Newcombe.
如果你知道有谁需要我的服务…嗯…也许是你的一个侄女?
If you know of anyone who could use me services... um... one of your nieces, perhaps?
萨曼莎，H夫人是谨慎的化身。
Samantha, Mrs. H is the soul of discretion.
要不是我把我的把手擦得锃亮，谁也不会知道她是谁。
One would never know she'd been but for the polish on my knobs.
哦,贾尔斯。
Oh, Giles.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
哦。
Oh.
试镜的事很抱歉，亲爱的。
Sorry about the audition, love.
我不知道我为什么要麻烦你。
Oh, I don't know why I bother.
“太年轻”。“太老了”。
"Too young." "Too old."
“太高了”。“太胖。”
"Too tall." "Too fat."
你说得对，宝贝儿。
You're just right, ducks.
我二十岁……三。
I'm twenty... three.
再过几年，我就完了。
Couple more years, and it's all over for me.
哦，你的时间很充裕。
Oh, you've plenty of time.
你无法想象这是什么感觉，哈里斯太太，总是担心自己的外表。
You can't imagine what it's like, Mrs. Harris, always having to worry about your looks.
灰姑娘，你为什么带破衣服来?
Hey, Cinderella, why'd you bring them rags?
我要去参加舞会……等我穿好衣服。
I will go to the ball... when I get me dress.
麻烦来了，大写的" a "
Oh, here comes trouble with a capital "A."
你好,阿奇。
Hello, Archie.
艾达，我要找的那个女孩。
Ada, the very girl I was after.
-我能为你做什么，宝贝儿?-别让我激动
- What can I do for you, ducks? - Now, don't get me excited.
你知道我心脏不好。
You know I've got a dodgy ticker.
哦，走开。
Oh, get away with you.
她比你有更大的计划。
She got bigger plans than you.
我看得出来。
I can see that.
你能帮我个忙照看一下春夏吗?
So, would you mind doing me a favor and look after Spring and Summer?
辛西娅，因为狗并不是最好的朋友。
Because Cynthia there's not exactly a dog's best friend.
继续。
Go on.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你绝对是个明星。
You are an absolute star.
你没事了。
And you're all right.
C ?好了，开始吧。
C? All right, here we go.
摇尾巴，宝贝。
Shake that tail, baby.
这就是我们，维。
That's what we are, Vi.
看不见的女人。
The invisible women.
为自己说话。
Speak for yourself.
他们看见我来了。
They see me coming. ♪ Mm! ♪
噢!
Oh!
请原谅，夫人。
Beg your pardon, milady.
夫人，这是我的账户。
Milady, um, my account.
我想知道你能不能结账。
I was wondering if you might settle up.
哦，我很抱歉，哈里斯太太。
Oh, I'm so sorry, Mrs. Harris.
恐怕我忘记去银行了。
I'm afraid I forgot to pop to the bank.
这场婚礼简直是噩梦。
This wedding is a nightmare.
每个人都说可以。
Everybody has said yes.
哦,嗯…你不会介意等到下个星期吧?
Oh, um... you wouldn't mind waiting until next week, would you?
呃，事情是这样的，现在有点紧迫，因为我需要…哦，是这个时间吗?
Well, uh, the thing is, it's become a bit pressing because I need to... Oh, is that the time?
事实上，哈里斯太太，恐怕我要减少你的工作时间了。
Actually, Mrs. Harris, I'm afraid I'm going to have to reduce your hours.
减少?请n不。夫人,请…现在我们都得节约，不是吗?
Reduce? N-No, please. Milady, please... Well, we all have to economize these days, don't we?
对不起。
Sorry.
我知道你在那里，女人，在黑暗和寒冷中。
I know you're there, woman, in the dark and cold.
我没事，小维。
I'm all right, Vi.
阿奇把我们送进了白城。
Archie has got us free into White City.
不，我还得补呢。
Oh, no, I've got all this mending.
——Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah。- n不。不,不,六世。
- Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah. - N-No. No, no, Vi.
6哦。
Vi... Oh.
给我们找点乐子。
Have us a bit of fun.
哦,上帝。看。
Oh, good Lord. Look.
这是一个信号。
It's a sign.
你有好建议吗?
You got a good tip?
是啊!
Yeah!
是的,我有!
Yeah, I have!
——嗯…excu……借口……-嗨。
- Um... excu... excuse... - Hey.
——对不起。-艾达，你想赌一把吗?
- Excuse me. - Ada, you fancy a flutter?
-是的。-要什么?
- Yeah. - What'll it be?
6号赌100英镑。
100 quid on number six.
赢。
To win.
一吨?
A ton?
看在迈克的份上，艾达，不，收起来。
For the love of Mike, Ada, no, put it away.
没有。6号。
No. Number six.
-请给我高级时装。-这只狗就像一袋骨头。
- Haute Couture, please. - The dog's a bag of bones.
屁股上有火箭它是赢不了的。
It couldn't win with a rocket up its arse.
你告诉她，阿奇。
You tell her, Archie.
她失去理智了。
She's lost her marbles.
不，这是高级时装。
No, it's Haute Couture.
这是一个信号。怎么会是别的呢?
It's a sign. How could it be anything else?
艾达，我干这行很久了，好吗?
Ada, girl, I've been doing this a long time, all right?
标志不能赢得比赛。
Signs don't win races.
直到今晚，他们才知道。
Not till tonight, they didn't.
我的钱很好。
My money's good.
算,请。
Count it, please.
是的。
Yeah.
这里。
Here.
我们开始吧。这很好。
Here we go. That's good.
我们找了个好地方。正确的。
Oh, we got a good spot. Right.
哦。祝我好运吧。
Oh. Wish me luck.
——哦,艾达。-来吧，高级定制。
- Oh, Ada. - Come on, Haute Couture.
哦，看，她领先了!
Oh, look, she's in the lead!
来吧!
Come on!
这是在前面。
It's in front.
来吧!
Come on!
《聪明的伯爵》《蓝色条纹》《暴风雨湾》
It's Clever Count, Blue Streak, and Stormy Bay.
你看…高级定制刚刚醒来，想起了她来这里的目的。
And would you look at that... Haute Couture has just woken up and remembered what she's here for.
嗯…向你致敬，姑娘。
Well... Hats off to you, girl.
你去争取了。
You went for it.
我去找圣约翰救护车。
I'll go find a St John's Ambulance.
他们可能喝了很多白兰地。
They might have a tot of brandy.
给我。
For me.
你是对的，维…那么多钱。
You were right, Vi... All that money.
我的埃迪会为我感到羞耻。
My Eddie'd be ashamed of me.
我马上回来，好吗?
I'll be right back, huh?
做梦也没什么，艾达，对吧?
Nothing wrong with dreaming, Ada, hmm?
当我来到伦敦，街道上铺满了我的梦想。
When I came to London, the streets were paved with my dreams.
这就是你。
That's what you are.
你是一个梦想家。
You're a dreamer.
就像你脸上的鼻子一样明显。
Plain as the nose on your face.
算了吧，小维，我没事。
Give over, Vi. I'm all right.
哈里斯太太吗?
Mrs. Harris?
爱德华·哈里斯夫人?
Mrs. Edward Harris?
是关于你丈夫的。
It's about your husband.
请坐下。
Sit down, please.
哈里斯中士直到4月19日才被宣布在行动中失踪。
Sergeant Harris wasn't declared missing in action until April the 19th.
是啊，我就是那时收到电报的。
Uh, yeah, that's when I got the telegram.
那天是他生日的第二天。
It's a day after his birthday.
啊,是的。
Ah, yes.
我们现在知道，波罗·利马326号航班坠毁于1944年3月2日，也就是说哈里斯中士死后被支付了近七周的工资。
Well, um, as we now know, Flight Polo Lima 326 crashed on March the 2nd, 1944, meaning that Sergeant Harris was paid for almost seven weeks after his death.
一天六先令。
At, um, six shillings a day.
这就是你来告诉我的吗?
Is that what you come to tell me?
过了这么久。
After all this time.
我的埃迪欠你工资吗?
That my Eddie owes you back pay?
他这辈子一分钱都没欠过。
When he never owed a penny in his life.
当他为国王和国家牺牲自己的生命。
When he give up his life for king and country.
你胆子真大。
You got a nerve.
来我家，喝我的茶，抹黑他的名声。
Coming into my home, drinking my tea, blackening his name.
——嗯…-你想要多少?
- Um... - How much do you want?
多少钱?然后你就可以走了。
How much? And then you can leave.
我觉得你理解错了。
I-I think you've got the wrong end of the stick.
哦,我吗?我马上就告诉你，你可以把棍子插哪儿-如果你不小心的话。-天啊，不。嗯,我,嗯…我是来给你钱的，哈里斯太太，
Oh, have I? Well, I'll tell you where you can shove your stick in a minute, - if you don't watch out. - Oh, golly, no. Um, I, uh... I'm here to give you money, Mrs. Harris,
-不是要从你那里拿走-我受够了…你想说什么?
- not-not to take it from you. - I've had enough of... What'd you say?
好的，没问题
Y-Yes. Righto.
你应该从1944年就开始领取战争寡妇抚恤金了。
Uh, you should have been receiving a-a war widow's pension since 1944.
算上那点小小的折扣，这是一笔不小的数目。
It comes to quite a tidy sum, uh, with that small deduction.
只要你没再婚就行。
So long as you haven't remarried.
算了吧
Oh, give over.
他随时都有可能回来，我看起来就像个查理。
He might have come back any minute, I'd have looked a right Charlie.
嗯…嗯…
Uh... well...
我想你最好坐下。
I suppose you'd better sit down.
还是喝杯茶吧。
Have that cup of tea after all.
嗯,没有牛奶。
Um, no milk.
她这辈子从没做过什么错事，先生。
She's never done a thing wrong her whole life, sir.
她因为一件衣服有点发疯，但现在没事了。
She went a bit crazy on account of some dress, but she's fine now.
没什么好担心的。
Nothing to worry about.
——哦,你好。-哈里斯太太?
- Oh, hello. - Mrs. Harris?
你是来告诉我我拿到王冠了吗?
You come to tell me I got the crown jewels?
她还是神志不清。
She's still not right in the head.
几乎。你交上来的那个钻石夹子…老板想奖励你做一个诚实的公民。
Almost. That diamond clip you handed in... The owner wants to give you a reward for being an honest citizen.
噢!她太诚实了，先生。
Oh! She is, sir, honest to a fault.
进来喝杯茶吧。
Come in and have a cup of tea.
请不要介意。谢谢你！
Don't mind if I do. Thank you.
来吧，小维，我们可以来个聚会。
Oh, come on, Vi. We can have a knees-up.
喂，等等我。
Oi, wait for me.
还有，你最好把香槟开了。
And, uh, you might want to break out the bubbly.
今天又走运了吗，阿奇?
You having another lucky day, Archie?
事实上，我是，你也是。
As a matter of fact, I am, and so are you.
消息传的很快。
News travels fast.
所以，你在两条腿的狗身上下的赌注…哦,y-yeah,不要…别担心。
So, that bet you put on that two-legged dog... Oh, y-yeah, don't... don't worry about that.
我恢复理智了。
I've come to me senses.
没有，老板在那里，所以我不得不拿钱，但我设法保留了10英镑。
No, the boss was there, so I had to take the money, but I managed to hold back a tenner.
你不该那么做的，阿奇。
You shouldn't have done that, Archie.
你可能会惹上麻烦。
You could have got into trouble.
一切都很顺利，哈里斯太太?
All tickety-boo, Mrs. Harris?
哦，对不起，我不知道你有客人。
Oh, sorry, I didn't realize you had company.
你好。这是怎么回事?
Hello. What's going on here?
——哦。-看在迈克的份上。
- Oh. - For the love of Mike.
-待会见-不，阿奇，阿奇
- Uh, I'll see you later. - Uh, no, Archie, Archie.
能让我单独待会儿吗?
Uh, can you just give me a moment?
这是私事。
It-it's personal.
-是水壶在叫吗?——是的。
- That the kettle calling? - Ah, righto.
怎么了? 出什么事了吗?
What's going on? Something up?
说来话长。
It's a long story.
你刚才说什么?
What were you saying?
所以，我拿了你的钱，把赌注压在了最后一场有把握的比赛上。
So, I took your money and put it on a sure thing in the last race.
,嗯…把你的木桩拿回来，再加一点。
And, um... your stake back and a wee bit more.
不，阿奇，我不能。
Oh, n-no, Archie, I couldn't.
——我……-这是你的钱。拿着。
- I... - It's your money. Take it.
我不能留着它，女人。
I can't keep it, woman.
PC Plod 在那里会有我的执照。来吧。
PC Plod in there would have my license. Come on.
答应我在军团跳支舞。
Just promise me a dance at the Legion.
谢谢你,阿奇。
Thanks, Archie.
感谢。
Much obliged.
啊呀。
Blimey.
我们在飞吗?
Are we flying?
女士们先生们，我们非常抱歉。
We're terribly sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
好像有一个引擎出了故障。
There seems to be a fault with one engine.
在我们试图解决这个问题时，会有一点延迟。
There will be a slight delay while we try and fix the problem.
延迟?
Delay?
多久?
How long?
我得在一天之内来回。
I've got to be there and back in a day.
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
巴黎。
Paris.
好了，巴黎，我来了。
Righto, Paris, here I come.
这是一条很长的路。
It's a fair old walk.
哦。嗯…你好。
Oh. Um... bonjour.
英国人?
English?
请求你的原谅吗?
Beg your pardon?
一个英国女人。
An Englishwoman.
嘿。
Hey.
谢谢你！是的。
Thank you. Yeah.
我是来买裙子的。
Um, I'm here to buy a dress.
迪奥的。
From Dior.
迪奥?
Dior?
啊,是的。我也是。
Ah, oui. Me also.
离迪奥远吗?
Is it far... Dior?
哦……20分钟。
Oh... 20 minutes.
但你喝完酒，两小时后。
Uh, but after you take wine, two hours.
我陪你去。
I walk you there.
明天早上,是吗?
Tomorrow morning, eh?
你饿了吗?
Are you hungry?
哦，不，不，谢谢。
Oh, no, no, thanks.
不,我不能
I couldn't, no.
好吧，接着说。
All right, go on, then.
哦,天哪。
Oh, blimey.
街上为什么有这么多垃圾?
Why is all this rubbish on the streets?
大老板作弊……-那个工人，是吗?-是的,是的。
The big boss cheats... - The worker, yes? - Yeah, yeah.
嗯,没有。这是结束了。
Well, no. It's over.
工人说:“不要了。”
The worker say, "No more."
他们已经受够了。
They've had enough.
收垃圾的人罢工了?
The binmen are on strike?
啊,是的。
Ah, yes.
现在整个巴黎，呃，闻起来…嗯,喜欢我。
Now all Paris, uh, smells, uh... uh, like me.
我们到了，我们到了。
Here we are, we've arrived.
伟大的迪奥品牌。
The great House of Dior.
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
祝你好运，英国小姐。
Good luck, English lady.
你是一个高贵的女人。
You are a noble woman.
记住，在法国，工人就是国王。
And remember, in France, the worker is king.
尽你所能拖住他们。她不会太久的，我肯定。
Hold them back as best you can. She won't be long, I'm sure.
对不起,夫人。
Excuse me, Madame.
哦,小姐!
Oh, miss!
你还好吗，亲爱的?笨拙的女孩!
You all right, love? Clumsy girl!
André，这是怎么回事?我可能会受伤的!
André, what is going on? I could have been hurt!
-你受伤了吗?——没有。对不起。
- Did you hurt yourself? - No. Sorry.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
-你确定吗?——是的。
- Are you sure? - Yes.
哦。
Oh.
小姐?
Miss?
小姐!
Miss!
-你还好吗?-别碰我!
- Are you all right? - Don't touch me!
没有,小姐。
No, miss.
奥奥!小姐!
Ooh-ooh! Miss!
小姐?
Miss?
给你。
Here you go.
你又一次救了我，夫人。
Once again, you save me, madame.
——哦。——我很抱歉。我很晚。
- Oh. - I'm sorry. I'm very late.
——哦。——谢谢。
- Oh. - Thank you.
没关系。只要你没受伤就行。
It's all right. As long as you're in one piece.
哦。
Ooh.
小心,小心,小心!
Careful, careful, careful!
哦,嗯…
Ooh, uh...
哦。对不起,亲爱的。
Oh. Excuse me, dear.
我在哪里可以找到这些衣服?
Where would I find the frocks?
恐怕您找错地址了，夫人。
I fear you have the wrong address, madame.
我叫人给你带路。
I will call someone to show you the way.
没有。不,不。
No. No, no.
对不起。我——我……我想买件连衣裙。
Sorry. I'm-I'm... I'm after a frock.
一个500磅重的。
One of them 500-pound ones.
请在这里等一下，马上会有人接待你的。
Please, if you could wait over here, somebody will attend you directly.
啊,伯爵夫人。
Ah, the Countess.
您好，冯·蒂森豪森男爵夫人。
Good day, Baroness von Tiesenhausen.
你好,夫人。
Hello, Madame.
现在,坚持下去。对不起。给你。
Now, hang on. Excuse me. Here you are.
夫人，我是第一个来的，比这一切都早。
Madame, I-I was here first, before any of this lot.
你没听说过排队吗?
Ain't you heard of queuing?
夫人Avallon !如此优雅，一如既往。
Madame Avallon! Such elegance, as always.
玛蒂尔德，你变了好多。
Mathilde, how you've changed.
对不起。看,我很抱歉。
Excuse me. Look, I'm sorry.
——请。——我——我……我不是一个小题大做的人，但在我的家乡，女店员很乐意为你服务。
- Please. - I'm-I'm... I'm not one to make a fuss, but where I come from, shopgirls are pleased to be of service.
女店员吗?
Shopgirls?
这个不幸的家伙是怎么被允许进来的?
How has this unfortunate creature been allowed in?
这位女士想买条裙子。这个女人显然是精神错乱了。
This lady wishes to buy a dress. The woman is clearly deranged.
指引她到一个合适的商店。
Direct her to a suitable shop.
一家百货商店。
A department store.
走了。
Go.
让我送你出去吧。
Uh, please let me escort you out.
不，不，不，等一下。
No, no, no, no, no, hang on a minute.
我已经英里。
I've come miles.
擦地板省下的每一分钱我都不知道该用什么来买这件衣服。
Saved every penny scrubbing floors and I don't know what so I can buy this frock.
一件克里斯汀·迪奥(Christian Dior)的礼服不是几分钱能买到的。
A Christian Dior gown is not for pennies.
马上把她移走。
Have her removed at once.
正确的。
Right.
如果你觉得我没钱…在那里。
If you think I ain't got the money... there.
哦là l.这是真钱，科尔伯特夫人。
Oh là l. It's real money, Madame Colbert.
要是每个人都能这么做就好了……您是迪奥先生吗?
If only everyone could do the same... Are you Mr. Dior?
不，我是会计部的福维尔先生。
Oh, oh, no, I'm Mr. Fauvel, accounts.
让我来帮你…今天，迪奥先生将展示他的十周年系列。
Let me help you with the... Today, Monsieur Dior will reveal his 10th Anniversary Collection.
在这种场合不能有任何减损。
Nothing must detract for this occasion.
打扰一下，chère女士，但如果您能作为我的客人来参观这些藏品，那将是我的荣幸。
Excuse me, chère madame, but it would be my honor to have you view the collection as my guest.
你就在那里。
There you are.
谢谢。
Merci.
好吗?
Shall we?
哦。
Oh.
姑娘们，你们绝对不会相信刚刚发生了什么。
Girls, you will never believe what's just happened.
有个伦敦来的清洁女工要去买条裙子。
There's a cleaning lady from London who's going to buy a dress.
-清洁女工?-是的，迪奥的礼服!
- A cleaning lady? - Yes, a Dior gown!
她带着所有的钱来了。
She arrived with all her money.
科尔伯特夫人不知道该把自己放在哪里。
And Madame Colbert didn't know where to put herself.
娜塔莎，你应该去看看她。她太棒了!
Natasha, you must come and see her. She's so wonderful!
看!看!
Look! Look!
女士们。
Ladies.
这里的。
It's here.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
她攒下所有的钱来看我们!
She saved up all her pennies to come and see us!
就是她，就在沙萨尼侯爵旁边。
There she is, just next to the Marquis de Chassagne.
你看到了什么?
You see?
这是怎么呢
What's going on?
回去工作!
Back to work!
快!
Quick!
当你看到你想要的裙子时，你可以把号码写在这里。
When you see the dress you want, you can write the number down here.
哦。
Oh.
我只是在欣赏你的扣眼。
Oh, I was just admiring your buttonhole.
哦。
Oh.
-我是露易丝·奥迪耶。——啊?
- It's Louise Odier. - Ah?
是的,它是可爱的。适当的气味。
Yes, it's lovely. Proper scent.
你是玫瑰花鉴赏家吗?
Are you a connoisseur of roses?
我丈夫埃迪在科文特花园的花市工作。
My husband Eddie worked at Covent Garden, the flower market.
你知道，他总是带些零零碎碎的东西回家。
He was always bringing home odds and ends, you know.
玫瑰是我的最爱。
Roses are me favorite.
你想给你妻子买条裙子吗?
You after a dress for your wife?
哦。幸运的女人。
Ooh. Lucky woman.
我妻子死了。
My wife is dead.
哦，请原谅，先生。
Oh, I do beg your pardon, sir.
我笨拙的木屐。
My clumsy clogs.
我的埃迪和所有人。
My Eddie and all.
哦,嗯…但是，是的，我和我妻子会一起来这里。
Oh, um... But yes, uh, my wife and I would come here together.
我喜欢看漂亮的衣服。
I like to see beautiful clothes.
当然还有美女。
And beautiful women, of course.
这不可能是真的。
This can't be true.
她再一次!
Her again!
这不会做。
This won't do.
对不起，阿瓦隆夫人。
I'm sorry, Madame Avallon.
我们会给你找个更合适的座位。
We will find you a more suitable seat.
不!这是我们平时的座位。
No! These are our usual seats.
我们会忍受这种侮辱，但不会就此结束。
We will endure this indignity but it won't end here.
哦，又来了。
Oh, here we go.
第一，律师诉讼。
Number one, the Bar Suit.
哦。
Ooh.
第二,
Number two,
第三,
Number three,
哦,太可爱了。
Oh, that's lovely.
哦。第四,妓女。
Oh. Number four, Cocotte.
42号,歌舞表演。
Number 42, Cabaret.
香槟色缎面雪纺晚宴礼服。
Dinner dress in champagne satin chiffon.
哦，你看。
Oh, will you look.
黑色缎面白色圆点鸡尾酒裙。
Cocktail dress in black satin with white polka dots.
哦,太可爱了。
Oh, that's lovely.
金星。
Vénus.
-那是什么数字?- 73。
- What number's that? - 73.
——金星。是的。- 73。金星。
- Vénus. Yes. - 73. Vénus.
-那是什么数字?- 89。
- What number's that? - 89.
诱惑。
Temptation.
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
万岁!
Bravo!
那个家伙是谁?
Who's that bloke?
那是大师本人，迪奥先生。
Well, that's the master himself, Monsieur Dior.
继续。
Go on.
他看起来像我的送奶工。
He looks like my milkman.
祝你好运，夫人。
Well, good luck, madame.
我希望你能找到你想要的。
I hope you find what you're looking for.
哦,好吧…这里。
Oh, well... Here.
你不想留着它吗?
You do not wish to keep it?
是的,这是可爱的没办法。谢谢你！
Yeah, it's-it's lovely. Thank you.
很高兴认识你。
Enchanté.
我不介意。
Don't mind me.
——是的,夫人?——哦。
- Yes, madame? - Oh.
你选好了吗?
Have you made your selection?
是的。嗯…请89号。诱惑。
Yes. Um... Number 89, please. Temptation.
当然。
Of course.
-请告诉我你的名字。-哈里斯。
- Your name, please. - Harris.
Ada哈里斯太太。销售的女孩吗?
Mrs. Ada Harris. Sales girl?
你知道我们的安排。
You know our arrangements.
我的道歉,夫人。
My apologies, madame.
——Excusez-moi。-哦,是的。
- Excusez-moi. - Oh, yeah.
是的，阿瓦隆夫人，有什么需要帮忙的吗?
Yes, Madame Avallon, how can I help you?
我已经做出了选择。
I've made my choice.
-很好，阿瓦隆夫人。-诱惑，第89题。
- Very good, Madame Avallon. - Temptation, number 89.
——啊。——哦。哈哈。
- Ah. - Oh. Ta-da.
哈里斯夫人，我很遗憾……《诱惑》有个问题。
Madame Harris, I regret... Well, there is a difficulty with Temptation.
似乎阿瓦隆夫人要求这样做。
It seems Madame Avallon demands it.
那是怎么做到的呢?你只有一条裙子?
How's that work, then? You only got the one dress?
对不起。夫人坚持独享。
I'm sorry. Madame insists on exclusivity.
阿瓦隆夫人是我们最忠实的客户之一。
Madame Avallon is one of our most devoted clients.
她的丈夫被称为“垃圾之王”。
And her husband is known as "The King of Rubbish."
但如果你不买东西就离开迪奥之家，我们会很遗憾的。
But we would be so sorry if you were to leave Maison Dior without a purchase.
你还在卡片上写了73号。
And you also wrote number 73 on your card.
——哦。——金星。
- Oh. - Vénus.
是啊，我从没想过还有比这更美的。
Yeah, I never thought nothing could be more beautiful.
直到我看到《诱惑》。
Not till I saw Temptation.
选得好，夫人。
An excellent choice, madame.
是的。多少钱?
Yeah. How much is it?
Vénus是60万法郎。
Vénus is 600,000 francs.
430磅。
430 pounds.
包起来。我还要赶飞机。
Wrap it up. I got a plane to catch.
我已经晚了一天了。
I'm a day late as it is.
哦，你不能要这件礼服。
Oh, you cannot have this gown.
别告诉我有人想要独占一切。
Oh, don't tell me someone wants that exclusive and all.
哈里斯夫人，每件衣服都是为客户量身定做的。
Mais Madame Harris, every dress is made and fitted individually for the client.
是的，这是高级时装。
Yes, this is haute couture.
当然，我们将复制您看到的Vénus，但问题是……给我做一个?
We will, of course, reproduce Vénus exactly as you saw it, but the thing is... Make me one?
那要花多长时间?
How long's that gonna take?
好吧，至少两周。
Well, at least two weeks.
哦。至少。
Ooh. At least.
有必要装几件。
Several fittings are necessary.
什么，离开我的人两周吗?
What, leave my people for a fortnight?
他们会找别人，然后我就流落街头了。
They'd find someone else, and then I'd be out on the streets.
那就去机场吧。
Vite, vite, to the airport, then.
如果你错过了航班，我不会原谅自己的。
I would not forgive myself if you missed your flight.
-什么，不穿我的裙子?——Excusez-moi。
- What, without my dress? - Excusez-moi.
也许你可以给你的朋友打电话?
Perhaps there is a friend you can call?
一个能帮你打扫卫生的人。
Someone who can assist you with your cleaning.
维有，但我已经考验过她的耐心了。
Well, uh, there's Vi, but I've tried her patience enough as it is.
总之，她不在电话上。
Anyway, she's not on the phone.
我们可以给她发个电报。
Uh, we might send her a telegram.
是的。是的,没错。
Yes. Yes, exactly.
哈里斯太太，也许可以鼓励裁缝师和裁缝加快工作速度。
Uh, Mrs. Harris, uh, it might be possible to encourage the cutter and seamstress to work a little faster.
维夫人能给你一周时间吗?
And Madame Vi could fill you in for one week, perhaps?
嗯…你真好，但我不能。
Well... you're kind, but I can't.
总之，我没地方住。
Anyway, I got nowhere to stay.
我只好不去了。
I'll have to give it a miss.
我妹妹不在。
My sister is away.
如果你……可以接受，你可以住在我那，我姐姐的房间。
If you... would accept, um, you could stay at my place, uh, in my sister's room.
你是个真正的天使，不是吗?
You're a proper angel, aren't you?
这是我的荣幸。
It'll be my pleasure.
我们可以马上给你量尺寸。
Um, we can have your measurements taken at once.
怎么了，科尔伯特夫人?
N'est-ce pas, Madame Colbert?
工作室无事可做。
The atelier has nothing to do.
但为了这一个订单?
But to devote itself to this one order?
现金交易，夫人。考虑到我们的情况下……很好，福维尔先生。看来现在是你说了算了。
A cash sale, Madame. Given our circumstances... Very well, Monsieur Fauvel. It seems you are in charge now.
哈里斯夫人。来了。
Come, Madame Harris. Come.
——哦。-我们必须快点。
- Oh. - We must be quick.
如果你们褶。
S'il vous plaît.
你去。不要只是站在那里。
Off you go. Don't just stand there.
哦。
Oh.
-布拉沃,夫人。-布拉沃。
- Bravo, madame. - Bravo.
——请夫人。——哦。
- Please, madame. - Oh.
当你买了一件Woolworths羽绒服，就不会有这么多的欢呼了。
You don't get all this hoo-ha when you buy a frock down Woolworths.
我可以告诉你，这种事在这里也不是每天都有。
Well, I can tell you such things do not happen every day here, either.
啊，那位必须穿裙子的女士……快,快,快。
Ah, the lady who must have her dress... Quick, quick, quick.
你的外套,请。
Your coat, please.
哦。
Oh.
-开衫衫。-是的，我的卡迪。
- Et le cardigan. - Yeah, me cardy.
非常感谢。
Thank you very much.
哦。
Oh.
十三。
Thirteen.
八十二年。
Eighty-two.
六十二年。
Sixty-two.
这位夫人有着模特的身材比例。
Madame has the proportions of a model.
更像是铁路模型。
Model railway, more like.
弯曲的部分之一
One of the curvy bits.
噢,谢谢你。
Oh, thank you.
非常感谢。
Thank you very much.
夫人呢?
Madame?
哦。
Oh.
我可以载你一程吗?
May I give you a lift?
哦，好吧，如果不麻烦的话。
Oh, well, if it's no bother.
没有。
No.
我要去福维尔先生家。
Uh, I'm going to Mr. Fauvel's.
18,是的。这很简单。
The 18th, yes. That's easy.
-哦，原谅我这么乱。——哦。
- Oh, forgive the mess. - Oh.
他是你的朋友吗，福维尔先生?
Is he a friend of yours, Mr. Fauvel?
没有。不，我只知道福维尔先生是给我签支票的人。
No. No, I-I know Mr. Fauvel only as the hand that signs my check.
哦。
Oh.
L’être et le néant。
L'être et le néant.
就是《存在与不存在》
It's, uh, "Being and Not Being."
我自己也喜欢蜷缩在一个多汁的谜团里。
I like to curl up with a juicy mystery meself.
哦，看，那是埃菲尔铁塔。
Oh, look, there's the Eiffel Tower.
哦,太可爱了。
Oh, that's lovely.
哦。
Oh.
这是歌剧。
That's the opera.
我帮您拿行李好吗?
May I help you with your luggage?
里面什么都没有。
Nothing in it yet.
哦。这是,不是吗?
Oh. That's something, innit?
哦。
Ooh.
我觉得他妹妹不知道拖把在哪里。
I don't think his sister knows where the mop is.
一定有个簸箕和刷子。
There must be a dustpan and brush somewhere.
嗯…哦。
Uh... Oh.
你不用这么做的，亲爱的。
Oh, you don't have to do that, love.
你一定有更重要的事情要做。
You must have better things to do.
不,不是真的。
No, not really.
défilé之后，总有一种空虚的感觉。
After the défilé, there's always a certain feeling of emptiness.
哦。
Oh.
好吧,鸭子。
All right, ducks.
哦。啊哈。
Oh. Aha.
现在我们开始工作了。
Now we're in business.
哦。
Oh.
发生了什么事?
What's happened?
-哈里斯太太?——你好,爱。
- Mrs. Harris? - Hello, love.
小姐。
Mademoiselle.
她是个好工人。
She's a good worker.
我总能给你找份工作，姑娘，如果你当模特不合适的话。
I can always find you a job, my girl, if the modeling don't work out.
我很尴尬，你看到了……不,不。
I am embarrassed beyond words that you have seen the state of... No, no.
我还没时间……不，拜托，没什么。
I haven't had time to... No, please, it was nothing.
噢!噢!请允许我……——我很抱歉。-不，对不起。
Oh! Oh! Allow me... - I'm sorry. - No, I'm sorry.
不，是我，我不应该……
No, it's me, I shouldn't have...
M-Mrs。哈里斯做了晚饭。
M-Mrs. Harris has cooked the dinner.
你们看起来需要一顿丰盛的大餐，你们俩。
You look like you could do with a good square meal, the pair of you.
娜塔莎小姐还有别的事要做。
Well, Mademoiselle Natasha has other engagements.
我相信迪奥的形象总是出现在派对或首映礼上。
I'm sure the face of Dior is always at a party or premiere.
稍后有一个soirée。
There's a soirée later.
来吧。Grub。
Come on. Grub's up.
我们到了。
Here we are.
别让它变冷了。
Don't let it get cold.
祝你有个好胃口。祝你有个好胃口。
- Bon appétit. - Bon appétit.
埃迪最喜欢的。
My Eddie's favorite.
要是有肉汁就更好了。
Be even better if we had a bit of gravy.
嗯，这道菜叫什么名字?
Um, and what's the dish named?
面拖烤肉。
Toad-in-the-hole.
青蛙的……?
Frog in the...?
在沟里。
In the ditch.
书真多啊，福维尔先生。
What a lot of books, Mr. Fauvel.
哦。
Oh.
娜塔莎有个谜一样的谋杀案。
Natasha's got a corker, a murder-mystery.
鸭子,你不?
Don't you, ducks?
存在与虚无。
Being and Nothingness.
你在读萨特?
You are reading Sartre?
我们应该说英语。
We should speak English.
哦,是的。当然。
Oh, yeah. Of course.
我很想知道娜塔莎小姐在读一本法国哲学家让-保罗·萨特写的书。——哦。
Um, I-I'm interested to learn that Mademoiselle Natasha is reading a book - by the French philosopher Jean-Paul Sartre. - Oh.
作者让我们考虑一下服务员的情况。
The author asks us to consider the case of the waiter.
服务员就是服务员吗，还是只是服务员的一种表达?
Is the waiter the waiter, or is it just an expression of what the waiter is?
同样的，我是会计吗，还是你给我的印象?
Um, similarly, am I the accountant, or is that an outward impression?
嗯，娜塔莎小姐是最美丽、最精致、最神圣的巴黎模特，还是……还是表象背后另有其人?
Um, is Mademoiselle Natasha only the most beautiful, the most exquisitely divine Parisian model, or... Or is there another person behind the facade?
是的。
Yes.
哈里斯太太是清洁工吗，还是她的存在有其他意义?
Is Mrs. Harris the cleaner, or is there more to define her existence?
完全一样。
Exactement.
我是巴特西的清洁工。没有秘密。
I'm a cleaner from Battersea. No mystery there.
不，你是一个梦想着拥有世界上最漂亮礼服的清洁工。
Uh, no, you're a cleaner who dreams of the most beautiful gown in the world.
哦,梦,是吗?
Oh, dreams, eh?
天知道薇收到那封漂亮的电报会说什么。
God knows what Vi is gonna say when she gets that blooming telegram.
哈里斯太太吗?
Mrs. Harris?
请随便拿我妹妹的衣服。
Uh, please help yourself to my sister's clothes.
哦,谢谢你,爱。嗯，我还好。
Oh, thanks, love. Um, I'm all right.
她会坚持的。
Uh, she would insist.
晚安
Good night.
晚安，亲爱的。
Night, love.
做个好梦。
Sweet dreams.
噢!
Ooh!
站直,夫人。
Stand straight, madame.
——哦!——不,但是……别动。你为什么要动?
- Oh! - Non, mais... Keep still. Why do you move?
对不起。对不起。
Sorry. Sorry.
我想和你谈谈改动的事玛格丽特公主?玛格丽特公主要求的。
I need to speak to you about some of the alterations Princess Margaret? Requested by Princess Margaret.
哦，我喜欢她。
Oh, I like her.
你可以从她的眼睛里看到一丝调皮。
You can see a little bit of mischief in her eye.
我们尊贵的客户要求我们极其谨慎。
Our distinguished clients demand our utmost discretion.
走吧，Carré先生。
Let's go, Monsieur Carré.
今天就到这里。
That's all for today.
这一点就很重要了，不是吗?
Little bit of that one goes a long way, don't it?
她吃什么?
What's eating her?
客户越重要，就越难搞定。
Well, the more grand the client, the more difficult.
他们的愿望必须始终得到满足，即使这意味着重新开始。
Their wishes must be accommodated always, even if it means starting afresh.
-货到付款。——哦!
- And they do not pay until delivery. - Oh!
如果。
If then.
要找的薪水太多了。
There are so many salaries to find.
面料、编结、刺绣、纽扣都必须是最好的。
The fabric, braid, embroidery, buttons all must be the very best.
每个人都有压力:
The pressure is on everyone:
对福维尔先生和帐目，对科尔伯特夫人和女裁缝，甚至对迪奥先生本人，总是这样的压力。
on Mr. Fauvel and the accounts, on Madame Colbert and the seamstresses, even on Monsieur Dior himself, always such pressure.
难怪福维尔先生看到我的小手提包会这么高兴。
Well, no wonder Mr. Fauvel was so pleased to see my little handbag.
事实上，哈里斯夫人，我们都担心迪奥品牌不能再这样下去了。
Well, in truth, Madame Harris, all of us fear the House of Dior cannot keep going this way.
是的,先生。
Oui, monsieur.
你还好吗，亲爱的?
You all right, love?
醒来吧,醒来吧。
Wakey, wakey.
他们找你。
They're calling for you.
哦。
Oh.
嗯,我很抱歉。
Um, I'm sorry.
-我只是累了。——嗯。
- I'm just tired. - Mm-hmm.
你可以去度个假。
You could do with a little holiday.
它已经给我带来了行善的力量。
It's doing me the power of good already.
是的，那太好了。
Yes, that would be nice.
一个人在海边，那里没有人……你在哪里?
By myself at the seaside, where nobody... Where are you?
对不起。
I'm sorry.
-我得走了。谢谢你！——哦。
- I must go. Thank you. - Oh.
对不起。
Sorry.
不，它不工作。
No, it doesn't work.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
您穿得怎么样，夫人?
How was your fitting, madame?
哦。
Oh.
这不是我的老朋友罗斯巴德先生吗。
Well, if it isn't my old pal, Mr. Rosebud.
我很遗憾我们没有正式介绍。
I regret we were not properly introduced.
Hypolite de Chassagne侯爵。
Marquis Hypolite de Chassagne.
哦。
Ooh.
艾达·哈里斯，巴特西的寡妇。
Ada Harris, widow of Battersea.
这个好人是谁?
Who's this fine fella?
-这是奈斯奎克。——哦。
- This is Nesquik. - Oh.
我相信迪奥先生能满足你的愿望?
So, I trust Monsieur Dior fulfills your heart's desire?
哦，他们真是太好了。
Oh, they're being ever so kind.
路易丝调研。我忘了名字了。
Louise Odier. I'd forgotten the name.
哦，我得给你看点东西。
Oh, I must show you something.
拜托，我不会耽误你太久的。
Please, I won't detain you long.
跟我说说，你在巴黎过得怎么样?
So, tell me, how are you enjoying your time in Paris?
我妻子很喜欢Marché aux Fleurs。
My wife adored the Marché aux Fleurs.
我们几乎到最后才回来。
We came here almost until the end.
到现在已经七年了。
It's been seven years now.
我们修补，但我们不会忘记。
We mend, but we don't forget.
当你向世界展示你的迪奥礼服时，它将是完美的。——哦。
When you display your Dior dress to the world, - it will be perfection. - Oh.
我朋友维觉得我疯了。
My pal Vi thinks I'm barmy.
“你要那件衣服干什么?”
"What do you want that dress for?
你打算什么时候穿?”
When are you gonna wear it?"
我不怀疑你想要这样一件高品质的礼服，即使只给你一个人看。
Oh, I do not question your desire for a gown of such quality, even if it is for your eyes alone.
不，不，正相反，我理解。
No, no, on the contrary, I understand.
你看，像这样的一朵玫瑰，或者像你这样的一件漂亮的长袍，他们……他们回忆起我们风华正茂的青春岁月。
You see, a rose like this one or a beautiful gown such as yours, they... they recall the days when we were in the full flower of our youth.
别现在就把我排除在外。
Oi, don't write me off just yet.
-哦，万分抱歉。-哦,不。
- Oh, a thousand apologies. - Oh, no.
请允许我赔罪。
Please, allow me to make amends.
今晚有安排吗?
Have you any arrangements for tonight?
瞧。
Voilà.
噢,谢谢你。
Oh, thank you.
来点香槟?
Some champagne?
哦，好的，请。
Uh, oh, yes, please.
就一滴
Just a drop.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
现在，你一定要尝尝鱼子酱。
Now, you-you must try the caviar.
哦。好吧
Oh. Right.
——干杯。——干杯。
- Cheers. - Cheers.
——不错,嗯?
- Nice, huh? - Mm.
哦,哦,你好!
Uh, oh, hello!
我觉得这身打扮骗不了任何人。你呢?
I don't think that getup's gonna fool anyone. Do you?
可爱的女孩。
Lovely girls.
嗯。很快，你就会看到有多可爱了。
Hmm. Soon, you'll see how lovely.
噢!哦。稳定。
Ooh! Oh. Steady on.
天啊，这些女孩都是自己挣钱养活自己的。
Blimey, they earn their keep, them girls.
至少我打扫的时候，不用笑着脱衣服了。
Well, least when I'm cleaning, I don't have to smile and strip as well.
晚安,哈里斯太太。
Bonsoir, Mrs. Harris.
娜塔莎。你好,爱。
Natasha. Hello, love.
你好。
Hello.
晚上好,小姐。
Bonsoir, mademoiselle.
-你想加入我们吗?-好的，谢谢。
- Would you like to join us? - Uh, yes, please.
那你和谁一起来的?
Who are you here with, then?
投资者。
Investors.
我逃脱了，但只是一瞬间。
I escape but only for a moment.
他们不会让你整天整夜都在做。
They don't half keep you at it, all day and all night as well.
对于Maison Dior来说，这是我的责任。
For Maison Dior, this is my obligation.
好吧，迪奥不仅仅是关于礼服。
Ah, well, Dior is not just about gowns.
它还体现了巴黎的优雅、颓废和优雅的生活方式，还有……而你，娜塔莎小姐，你是迪奥王冠上的一颗宝石。
It's also about elegance and decadence and the savoir-vivre of Paris, and... and you, Mademoiselle Natasha, you are the jewel of this Dior crown.
嗯，我更喜欢在家看书。
Well, I would prefer to be at home with a book.
你这么说真有趣。
It's funny you should say that.
我把福维尔先生留在家里看书了。
I've left Mr. Fauvel at home reading a book.
它被称为…“好管闲事”?就像这样。
It was called... "Nosy"? Something like that.
- La nausee ?——不知道。
- La nausée? - Don't know.
为什么他要容忍时尚公司，而不是萨特和智慧的世界?
Why does he tolerate the fashion house compared to his world of Sartre and the intellect?
我想他有他的理由。
Well, I-I think he has his reasons.
你喜欢这场演出吗?
Do you enjoy the show?
是的,一个…最后那个，她…她和我蒂尔达阿姨长得一模一样。
Yeah, the one... the one at the end, she... she's a dead ringer for my Aunt Tilda.
从后面。
From behind.
这很好，但我该走了。
Well, this was lovely, but I should go.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
哦，等一下，亲爱的。
Oh, just-just a minute, love.
你的刘海。
Your fringe.
有一个小缺口。
There's a little gap.
就是这样。
That's it.
你已经征服了他。
You have made a conquest.
哦，走开。
Oh, get away with you.
你敢于追逐梦想，哈里斯太太。
You dare to follow your dreams, Mrs. Harris.
-布拉沃。——哦。
- Bravo. - Oh.
再见,爱。
Bye, love.
——晚安。——晚安,娜塔莎。
- Bonsoir. - Bonsoir, Natasha.
-再来点香槟?-哦，就一点。
- Some more champagne? - Oh, just a drop.
我九点半要去试衣。
I've got me fitting at 9:30.
哦,上帝!
Oh, God!
哦,戈登•班尼特!
Oh, Gordon Bennett!
哦,哦!
Oh, oh!
噢!哦!
Oh! Oh!
小心!
Careful!
哦,哦,哦!
Oh, oh, oh!
哦!
Oh!
愚蠢的白痴!
Stupid cretin!
白痴!清楚了!
Idiot! Clear off!
出去!出去!Avallon出来!
Out! Out! Avallon out!
我真不敢相信。
I can't believe this.
阿瓦隆，你这个肮脏的臭家伙!
Avallon, you dirty stinker!
把他扔进垃圾桶!
Chuck him in the bin!
对不起!
Sorry!
对不起。对不起。
Sorry. Sorry.
-我很抱歉。-不不不
- I'm so sorry. - No, no, no.
这是不可能的，完全不可能。
This is not possible, not at all.
不不不，求你了，我…我从不迟到。我…R-Really,我不是。我从不迟到。对不起。
No, no, no, please, I-I'm... I'm never late. I... R-Really, I'm not. I'm never late. Sorry.
你要求我们"快，快，快"
You demand of us, "Vite, vite, vite,"
但你没有尊重。
but you have no respect.
不，这是不可能的。
No, this cannot be done.
不客气。
Not at all.
现在我离开了。
Now I depart.
这是完成了。
This is finished.
不，不，不。拜托，拜托，拜托，Carré先生。
No, no, no, no. Please, please, p-please, Mr. Carré.
科尔伯特夫人,请。
Madame Colbert, please.
Carré先生拒绝继续。
Monsieur Carré refuses to proceed.
我该怎么办?
What can I do?
没有。不，当然，我…不,我理解。
No. No, of course, I... No, I understand.
是的，我当然知道。我做的事。
Yeah, of course I do. I do.
迪奥，它不只是一件礼服。
Dior, it's-it's not just a gown.
这是,嗯……一切都是优雅，精明，诸如此类。
It's, um... It's all the elegance and-and the savvy and all that.
我知道。
I-I know that.
我想办法退还您的押金。
I will see what can be done to return your deposit.
不,我不…所以,Carre先生……
No, I don't... So, Monsieur Carré...
我…我不希望…我不要我的存款。
I-I... I don't want... I don't want me deposit.
香槟查理，对吧?
Right Champagne Charlie, aren't I?
我活该，过着奢华的生活。
Serves me right, living the high life.
我尊重你们，你们所有人。
I do respect you, all of you.
没关系,是吗?
Never mind, eh?
谢谢你,爱。
Thanks, love.
你真是太好了。
You've been ever so kind.
哈里斯夫人，你走之前要不要去看看工作室?
Madame Harris, would you care to see the atelier before you leave?
哦。
Ooh.
你好,夫人。-你好。
- Bonjour, mesdames. - Bonjour.
所以，这个房间是用来切的。
So, this room is for cutting.
-你好。——早上。
- Bonjour. - Morning.
结构du时装。
Structure du couture.
非结构化的时装。
Unstructured couture.
珠缀。
Passementerie.
Plumassier。
Plumassier.
Broderie。
Broderie.
哈里斯夫人吗?
Mrs Harris?
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
这不是缝纫。
It's not sewing.
它让月光。
It's making moonlight.
我去天堂了吗?
Have I gone to heaven?
哈里斯太太问她是不是去天堂了。
Mrs Harris asked if she's gone to heaven.
女士们!
Ladies!
快,快。回去工作!
Quick, quick. Back to work!
你觉得这种布料适合阿佛洛狄忒吗?
Do you think this fabric could work well for Aphrodite?
是的，我喜欢这个颜色。
Yes, I love the color.
我可以带Carré先生去吗?——当然。
- May I show Monsieur Carré? - Certainly.
Carré先生，这种面料更豪华。
Monsieur Carré, this fabric is even more luxurious.
也许我们可以用它来…?
Perhaps we could use it for...?
我们找到了一些共同点，小麻雀和我。
We have found some common ground, the little sparrow and I.
她是个能干的女裁缝。
She's a capable seamstress.
按钮会出什么问题?
What could go wrong with buttons?
自从le maître发布了他的第一个系列以来，我已经在迪奥的肩膀上日夜站了十年。
I have stood at Monsieur Dior's shoulder day and night for ten years, since le maître unveiled his first collection.
世界上最时髦的女人来到蒙田大道。
The most fashionable women in the world come to the Avenue Montaigne.
皇室成员和交际花，瘦的，胖的，年轻的，年老的，丑陋的，或者有什么说不上来的。
Royalty and courtesans, thin, fat, young, old, ugly, or with a certain je ne sais quoi.
嗯。
Hmm.
但还有你，哈里斯太太。
But then there is you, Mrs. Harris.
我当导演这么久，还从没遇到过像你这样的人。
All my time as directress, I have never encountered anyone like you.
哦。
Oh.
在我的生活中，你会遇到各种各样的人。
In my walk of life, you meet all sorts.
作为一个好老板，我必须让我的员工开心，他们的愿望就是完成你的衣服。
As a good boss, I must keep my workers happy, and their wish is to complete your dress.
哦。感谢。
Oh. Much obliged.
所以你能礼貌地回答我的问题吗?
So you will do me the courtesy of answering my questions, no?
是的。
Yeah.
哦。干杯。干杯!
Oh. Bottoms up. Cheers!
你为什么来这里，哈里斯太太?
Why do you come here, Mrs. Harris?
Évidemment，富人和有头衔的人必须被看到，崇拜，模仿。
Évidemment, the rich and titled must be seen, admired, copied.
但是这条你非常渴望的Dior裙子，你会在哪里穿呢?
But this Dior dress that you desire so much, where will you wear it?
是在维也纳歌剧舞会还是夏洛特女王的舞会?
At the Vienna Opera Ball or Queen Charlotte's?
你会用它来擦地板，还是会把它关在你的小衣柜里?
Will you wear it to polish floors, or will you keep it shut in your little wardrobe?
迪奥的裙子是为了让人惊喜而设计的。
A Dior dress is designed to astonish and delight.
你要怎么做，哈里斯太太?
How will you do that, Mrs. Harris?
你……原谅我这么说，但你不是什么人，隐形人。
You... Forgive me for saying this, but you are nobody, invisible.
你将如何赋予这条裙子它应有的生命?
How will you give this dress the life it deserves?
这是我的梦想。
It's my dream.
我的钱和其他人的一样好。
And my money's as good as anybody else's.
当然可以。嗯。
Bien sûr. Hmm.
你可以买下你的梦想，但你会用它做什么呢?
You may buy your dream, but what will you do with it?
是的,可以。
Oui, entrez.
哈里斯太太，这是给你的。
Mrs. Harris, these are for you.
哦。
Ooh.
勒侯爵先生送的。
From Monsieur le Marquis.
哦。
Oh.
他希望你明天来喝茶。
He wishes that you visit for tea tomorrow.
沙萨尼侯爵?
Le Marquis de Chassagne?
但是…他收到没有。
But... he receives nobody.
但我是个无名小卒，不是吗?
But I am nobody, aren't I?
我从没想过像迪奥这样的地方会有问题。
I never thought a place like Dior would have problems.
我看到那条裙子，就想到了梦想和童话。
I saw that dress, and I thought of dreams and fairy tales.
是的，我们就像童话故事。
Yes, we are like a fairy tale.
可爱但不真实。
Lovely but not real.
今天有这个地方吗?
Is there a place for that today?
哦，我们需要梦想。
Oh, we need our dreams.
现在更是如此。
Now more than ever.
如果你能拥有这个，为什么还要迪奥?
If you can have this, why do you need Dior?
高级时装对我们和我们的客户来说是一种虚荣。
Haute couture is a vanity for us and our clients.
事实上，我不认为迪奥品牌能生存下去。
In truth, I don't think the House of Dior can survive.
不，亲爱的，那太悲剧了。
No, love, that would be a tragedy.
你不能让这种事发生。
You can't allow that to happen.
嗯，我有个主意，但需要一种新的思维方式。
Well, I have an idea, but it requires a new way of thinking.
什么?专横的靴子挡道了?
What? Bossy Boots in the way?
科尔伯特夫人，她守卫圣殿。
Madame Colbert, she guards the temple.
她让一个清洁女工买了一件迪奥的礼服。
She let a cleaning lady buy a Dior gown.
有钱能使鬼推磨
Money talks.
是的，你知道它说什么，所以你必须做点什么。
Yes, and you know what it says, so you have to do something about it.
我知道你可以。你真是太聪明了。
I know you can. You're ever so clever.
你是唯一相信的人。
You're the only one who believes.
这是怎么回事?
What's going on here?
看起来像首映礼。
It looks like a premiere.
噢!
Ooh!
哦,令人兴奋。
Oh, exciting.
那是让·法布尔，电影明星。
Oh, that's Jean Fabre, the movie star.
难道他不知道吗?
Mm, and don't he know it?
哦,这是娜塔莎!噢!
Oh, it's Natasha! Oh!
-娜塔莎!奥奥!-你在干什么?不,不。
- Natasha! Ooh-ooh! - What are you doing? No, no.
-娜塔莎!——没有。
- Natasha! - No.
你好。
Hello.
晚上好，哈里斯太太。
Good evening, Mrs. Harris.
你看起来可爱。
You look lovely.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
晚上好,先生Fauvel。
Bonsoir, Monsieur Fauvel.
晚上好。我们不知道你是…我们只是路过。
Bonsoir. Um, we didn't know you were, uh... We were just passing.
你们俩今晚有什么安排?
So, what are you two doing this evening?
——哦,嗯…哦。娜塔莎。
- Oh, well... Oh. - Natasha.
对不起。我必须走了。
I'm sorry. I-I must go.
很高兴见到你。
It was great to see you.
哦,是的。再见,爱。
Oh, yeah. Ta-ta, love.
我想这只是作秀。
I think it's just for show.
我不确定他是否适合结婚。
I'm not sure that he's the marrying kind.
哈里斯太太，我求你了，在我被羞辱死之前，你得停止这事。-哦…请。够了!
Mrs. Harris, I-I beg of you, you-you need to stop this coupling thing - before I die of humiliation. - Oh... Please. Enough!
好吧。我不是聋子。
All right. I'm not deaf.
我当然爱上娜塔莎了。
Of course I'm in love with Natasha.
我是说，谁不是呢?
I mean, who isn't?
我很抱歉，但生活不全是月光和电影。
I'm sorry, but life is not all moonlight and movies.
为什么不能呢?
Why can't it be?
我一个人待了太久，希望自己的生命快点结束。
I've spent too long on my own, wishing my life away.
你不会想做同样的事情。
You don't want to do the same thing.
哈里斯太太，我觉得你的浪漫之梦很适合巴黎。
Mrs. Harris, I think your dreams of romance fit Paris very well.
原谅我，也许是你想要恋爱。
Forgive me, but perhaps it is you who wishes to be in love.
你必须关注自己的内心。
You who must attend to your own heart.
来吧，艾迪，说点什么，亲爱的。
Come on, Eddie, say something, love.
试着弄明白这一切，因为我做不到。
Try and make some sense of this, 'cause I can't.
这都是你干的。
This is all your doing.
准备好带你的女朋友去巴黎。
Coming up with the readies to get your girl to Paris.
巴黎。
Paris.
满足一个人吗?
To meet someone?
啊。
Ah.
好吗?
Shall we?
迪奥的姑娘们说我的裙子快做好了。
The girls at Dior say my dress is almost finished.
是的。可能明天吧。
Yeah. Maybe tomorrow.
然后我会…我要回家了。
And then I'll be... I'll be back off home.
是的,它是可爱的。
Yeah, it's lovely.
真的,真的可爱。
Really, really lovely.
欢迎那位垃圾女士。
That rubbish lady's welcome to hers.
讽刺的是。
And here's the irony.
迪奥先生为美丽的女人创作了优美的诗歌，赞美她们的清新和完美，却看到她们被破旧的衣服带走。
Monsieur Dior makes exquisite poems for beautiful women in celebration of their freshness and perfection only to see them carried away by old frumps.
就像那个可怕的阿瓦隆夫人。
Like that dreadful Madame Avallon.
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
然而，当然，也有一些人保持着某种难以言喻的魅力，一种难以言喻的诱惑。
Whereas, of course, there are those who retain a certain je ne sais quoi, an indefinable allure.
啊。
Ah.
请允许我为您奉上一壶英国茶。
Allow me to present to you a pot of English tea.
哦，只是工作。
Oh, just the job.
嗯。谢谢,玛丽亚。
Hmm. Merci, Maria.
现在我们让大麻酿出来。
And now we let the pot brew.
-这是正确的形式，对吗?-没错。
- Is that the correct form, yes? - That's the ticket.
我得给你织个茶壶套。
I'll have to knit you a tea cozy.
是的，由于我一直不清楚的原因，我在六岁的时候被送到温莎的一所寄宿学校，在那里我养成了对茶和一切英国事物的爱好。
Yes, for reasons that were never clear to me, I was sent as a boy of six to a boarding school in Windsor, and that's where I acquired a taste for tea and of all things English.
等的时候，我想让你看个东西。
While we wait, there's something I would like you to see.
跟我来。
Come with me.
在那里。
There.
哦。哦。
Oh. Oh.
六岁了，可怜的小家伙。
Six years old, you poor mite.
嗯，家里也好不到哪里去。
Well, home was not much better.
但是，是的，我很痛苦。
But yes, I suffered.
我是个软弱的小男孩，总是被人欺负。
I was a weak little boy, perpetually bullied.
哦。
Oh.
你知道吗，我一看到你，我心里就有了共鸣。
You know, as soon as I saw you, I felt this connection in my heart.
我不知道，也许……你的微笑，你的善良，你的……你的英语幽默。
I don't know, perhaps... your smile, your kindness, your... your English humor.
我知道你让我想起了一个人，一个对我很重要的人，但是谁?
I knew you reminded me of someone, someone very dear to me, but who?
就在昨天，当我回忆的时候，我才意识到有一个人在照顾我。
And only yesterday, as I searched my memories, did I realize there was a person who took care of me.
她的一生是一个不知疲倦的苦工，但她找到时间安慰我，擦干我的眼泪。
Her life was one of tireless drudgery, and yet she found the time to comfort me and dry my tears.
她叫马多克斯太太，但我们以前都叫她拖把太太。
Her name was Mrs. Maddox, but we used to call her Mrs. Mops.
在那里。
There.
我让你想起了莫普太太?
I-I remind you of Mrs. Mops?
——啊,是的。——清洁工吗?
- Ah, yes. - The cleaner?
莫普斯太太擦干我的眼泪，让我再次微笑，就像你，哈里斯太太，这几天一样。
Mrs. Mops dried my tears and made me smile again, as you have, Mrs. Harris, these past few days.
我真希望戴尔芬能认识你。
I do wish my Delphine could have known you.
你看，你安慰那些需要帮助的人，却不求任何回报。
You see, you give comfort to those in need without asking anything in return.
是这样吗?
Is that right?
你是这样看我的吗?
Is that how you see me?
你明白我们之间为什么有联系了吧?
You see why there is a connection between us?
现在，我们来喝杯英式茶，好吗?
Now, let's have a nice cup of English tea, shall we?
不用了，谢谢。
Uh, no, thank you.
我最好现在就走。
I'd best be getting along.
他们在发廊等我。
They're expecting me at the salon.
Avallon,肮脏的老板!
Avallon, dirty boss!
阿瓦隆，在垃圾箱里!
Avallon, in the bin!
我们会让你腐烂的，阿瓦隆!
We will make you rot, Avallon!
玛格丽特?
Marguerite?
有什么事吗?
What's the matter?
在你去。
In you go.
你放这些女孩走是怎么回事?
What's this about you letting all these girls go?
哦。你还好吗，亲爱的?
Ooh. You all right, love?
如果他们像你一样免费工作，那就没有必要了。
It would not be necessary if they worked for free, as you do.
他们需要工作。他们还要养家糊口。
They need their jobs. They've got families to feed.
Excusez-moi。
Excusez-moi.
是的，很遗憾，但这不关你的事。
Yes, it is very sad, but this is not of your concern.
好吧，我们走着瞧吧。
Well, we'll see about that.
拜托，夫人，你已经把这里的每个角落都翻遍了。
Please, madame, you have reached into every corner of this establishment.
我坚持要求你尊重我们的隐私。
Now, I insist that you respect our privacy.
嗯。
Hmm.
你要去哪儿，哈里斯太太?
Where are you going, Mrs. Harris?
去见老板。
To see the boss.
——你不能。没有。-来吧，姑娘们。
- You cannot. No. - Come on, girls.
——请。没有。,跟我来。轻快地,急速地。
- Please. No. - Follow me. Vite, vite.
来吧，姑娘们。来吧。
Here we go, girls. Come on.
下来的工具。
Down tools.
来，到我后面来。加入我们的行列。
Come on, get behind me. Join us.
是啊，今天有个很重要的工作。
Yeah, got a really important job today.
-哦，你看起来很可爱，但是拜托-哈里斯太太!
- Ooh, you look lovely, but come on. - Mrs. Harris!
-来为我做这件事。-哈里斯太太!
- Come and do this for me. - Mrs. Harris!
你必须立刻停止这件事。
You must stop this at once.
你根本不知道自己在做什么。
You have no idea what you are doing.
哦，是的，我喜欢。
Oh, yes, I do.
这叫罢工。
It's called a strike.
好了，女士们，来吧。拜托!
Right, ladies, come on. Please!
跟我来。没时间了，亲爱的。
Follow me. No time for that, dear.
Oi !没必要推推搡搡。来吧。
Oi! No need to push and shove. Come on.
呆在这儿!
Stay here!
玛格丽特，你怎么了?
Marguerite, what's got into you?
你呆在这里!
You stay here!
站起来，André。还有工作要做。
On your feet, André. There's work to be done.
这都是你的错，福维尔先生。做点什么。
This is all your fault, Monsieur Fauvel. Do something.
你觉得我能阻止这个女人吗?
Do you think I can stop this woman?
逮捕她!
Arrest her!
我是共产主义者，夫人。我站在她这边。
I'm a communist, Madame. I'm on her side.
让我通过吧!
Let me pass!
哈里斯太太，求你了，别这么做。
Mrs. Harris, I beg of you, do not do this.
这是你的机会，André，在你的一生中，你能得到多少机会呢?——不,看起来……迪奥先生，请占用您十分钟的时间。
This is your chance, André, and how many chances - do you get in your lifetime? - No, look... Monsieur Dior, ten minutes of your time, please.
这就是福维尔先生拯救公司所需要的一切。
That's all Mr. Fauvel needs to save the company.
我吗?我怎么…迪奥先生，对不起。
Me? What do I-I... Monsieur Dior, I am sorry.
继续,宠物。你能做到的。告诉他你的计划。
Go on, pet. You can do it. Tell him your plan.
——嗯…——继续。
- Uh... - Go on.
一个没有优雅，没有区别，没有迪奥的世界，不，这是不可能的。
A world without elegance, without distinction, without Dior, no, it's impossible.
然而，迪奥品牌如何才能克服目前的问题呢?
Yet how can the House of Dior surmount its current problems?
迪奥不是让全世界都来到蒙田大道，而是要让所有人都能买到迪奥的产品。
Rather than the world coming to Avenue Montaigne, Dior must go out to the world with a range of goods available to all.
香水，长筒袜，奢侈品…普通女人都买得起。
Uh, perfume, stockings, luxury that... that the ordinary woman can afford.
那将不再是迪奥之家。
That would no longer be the House of Dior.
它将不再是高级时装。
It would no longer be haute couture.
我们的声誉建立在我们的独家。
Our reputation is founded on our exclusivity.
停下来,性格。
Stop, Loulou.
是的。
Oui.
福维尔先生，你有十分钟的时间。
Monsieur Fauvel, you have ten minutes.
什么?
What?
哦,对了。
Oh, right.
祝你好运,爱。
Good luck, love.
你也一样。
And you as well.
谢谢。
Merci.
我们罢工赢了!
We've won the strike!
把阿瓦隆扔进监狱!
Throw Avallon in jail!
为工人们干杯!
Here's to the workers!
十年前，当迪奥(House of Dior)推出第一个系列时，排他性是关键，这是真的。
Ten years ago, when the House of Dior presented its first collection, exclusivity was key, it's true.
但今天，出现了一个新女性，一个现代女性，她知道自己想要什么，需要能够买到它。
But today, there's a new woman, a modern woman who knows what she wants and needs to be able to buy it.
今天，哈里斯太太来了。
Today, there's Mrs. Harris.
哦。
Oh.
maître同意我们的计划意味着，我们不仅不会失去工作，还需要更多的工作。
The maître's agreement to our plan means that, far from losing jobs, we will need more.
很多很多更多。
Many, many more.
万岁!
Bravo!
你确定是这条街吗?
Are you sure this is the right street?
必须。我每个月都在这里给她寄支票。
Must be. This is where I send her check every month.
里面不会有一粒灰尘。
There won't be a speck of dust inside.
你可以用生命来打赌。
You can bet your life.
这是它。
This is it.
没有。
No.
别烦我。
Leave me in peace.
只是一个字。
Just a word.
为什么?我承认。
Why? I concede.
胜利属于你，哈里斯太太。
The victory is yours, Mrs. Harris.
科尔伯特夫人，求你了。
Madame Colbert, I beg you.
那里是谁?
Who's there?
没什么，别担心。我马上回来。
It's nothing, don't worry. I'll be right back.
他们想要什么?
What do they want?
别担心。
Don't worry.
我的丈夫…他在战争中受伤了。
My husband... He was damaged in the war.
他需要经常照料。
He requires constant care.
你要么做，要么付钱。
Which you either do or pay for.
难怪你在前面摆那么多。
No wonder you got all that front on you.
请说你想要什么。
Say what you want, please.
夫人，很抱歉冒犯了您。
Madame, I'm so sorry to have offended you.
我对您怀有崇高的敬意，我从未想过强迫您改变……你描述的未来很有道理，但我不想成为其中的一部分。
I hold you in the highest regard, and it was never my intention to force a change on... The future you describe makes perfect sense, but I want no part of it.
哦,不,请。
Uh, no, please.
你千万别想离开。
You must not think of leaving.
也许我在我的岗位上呆得太久了，在伟大的男人背后做了太久的隐形女人。
Perhaps I have been too long in my post, too long the invisible woman behind the great man.
战斗说话。
Fighting talk.
你走到哪里,女孩。
You go, girl.
我不像你那样是个革命者，哈里斯太太。
I'm not a revolutionary like you, Mrs. Harris.
我只是想一个人待着。
I simply wish to be left alone.
嗯,那是……这一切都很好，而且上帝知道这是你应得的，但你知道没有你，它会崩溃的，不是吗?
Well, that's... that's all fine and dandy, and Lord knows you deserve it, but you know it'll fall apart without you, don't you?
相信我，我看过很多次了。
Trust me, I've seen it over and over.
当这位女士起身离开时，这位先生坚持不了十分钟。
When the lady ups and leaves, the gent don't last ten minutes.
你需要的。
You're needed.
现在更是如此。
Now more than ever.
还有谁能保证一切正常呢?
Who else is gonna keep things up to scratch?
不是André或迪奥先生。
Not André or Monsieur Dior.
两个男人能知道什么?
What would two men know about that?
你和我，你知道，我们是一模一样的。
You and me, you know, we're two peas in a pod.
我们清理每个人的烂摊子，把花园里的一切都弄得很漂亮。
We clean up everybody's mess and make everything in the garden lovely.
我们是他们依赖的人。
We're the ones they rely on.
他们甚至不知道我们是干什么的，但就像鸡蛋就是鸡蛋一样，没有我们，一切都会完蛋。
They don't even know what we do, but as sure as eggs is eggs, without us, it all goes tits up.
也许需要与le maître进行一次对话。
Perhaps a conversation with le maître is required.
也许。
Perhaps.
明天，你告诉娜塔莎你的感受。
And tomorrow, you tell Natasha how you feel.
但是娜塔莎小姐已经离开迪奥了。
Oh, but Mademoiselle Natasha has left Dior.
她的离开巴黎。
She's leaving Paris.
和你一样，哈里斯太太，她也想追寻自己的梦想。
Like you, Mrs. Harris, she wishes to follow her dream.
继续找,爱。她一定在这里的某个地方。
Keep looking, love. She's got to be here somewhere.
她走了。这是最好的选择。
She's gone. It's for the best.
如果你不……你马上就会被狠狠地揍一顿。坚持下去。
You're gonna get yourself a good clip round the ear in a minute if you don't... Hang on.
等一下。我知道。
Hang on a minute. I know.
这里。
Here.
哦。
Oh.
哦。夫人迪奥。
Oh. Madame Dior.
Magnifique。
Magnifique.
哦，好吧，你自己也不错。
Oh, well, not so bad yourself.
我们在找一个女孩。
Uh, we're looking for a girl.
嗯,她是……她有点不高兴。
Um, she's... she's a bit upset.
嗯…你见过的最聪明，最可爱的女人。
Um... The most intelligent, the most adorable woman you've ever seen.
她是迪奥的模特。
She's a Dior model.
那边那个?
That one over there?
——哦,娜塔莎。娜塔莎。
- Oh, Natasha. - Natasha.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
这种生活，不适合我。
This life, it's-it's not for me.
不，当然不是。
No, of course it isn't.
被钉在基座上，像个漂亮的洋娃娃一样到处招摇。
Stuck on a pedestal, paraded around like a beautiful doll.
谁都看得出来那女孩不想要。
Anyone can see the girl doesn't want it.
哈里斯太太说得对。
Mrs. Harris is right.
我不是这样的人。
It's not who I am.
正如萨特所说，你会发现自己在être-en-soi和être-pour-soi之间存在矛盾。
As Sartre would say, y-you find yourself conflicted between être-en-soi et être-pour-soi.
介于"自为"和"自在"之间
Between "for itself" and "in itself."
Être-en-soi是指人类生活中涉及意识的那些方面，而物理事实是être-pour-soi。
Être-en-soi being those aspects of human life that involves consciousness, whereas physical facts are être-pour-soi.
存在主义者!
Existentialists!
在这种情况下，事情就会变回原来的样子。
In which case, things would be what they are not.
没错。
Exactement.
物是人非，物是人非。
Things are what they are not, and they're not what they're not.
André，看在上帝的份上，吻她吧。
André, for God's sake, just kiss her.
是的。看在上帝的份上，吻我吧。
Yes. For God's sake, just kiss me.
嗯。
Hmm.
娜塔莎，和我一起留在巴黎吧。
Stay in Paris with me, Natasha.
但我已经告诉迪奥先生了。
But I have already told Monsieur Dior.
你仍然可以学习哲学。
You can still study philosophy.
使不可见的东西变得可见。
To make the invisible visible.
你没在巴黎找到爱情吗，迪奥夫人?
You did not find love in Paris, Madame Dior?
-哦,不。没有。——哦。
- Oh, no. No. - Oh.
我以为已经太晚了，但是……现在我不太确定了。
I thought it was too late, but... now I'm not so sure.
——你好,爱。——你好,艾达。
- Hello, love. - Hello, Ada.
哦。好吧，好吧。
Oh. All right, all right.
戈登·班尼特。
Gordon Bennett.
好吧。
All right.
哦,你好,爱。进来。
Oh, hello, love. Come in.
谢天谢地你回来了。
Oh, thank God you're back.
哦，不会太久。
Oh, well, not long.
你想喝杯茶吗?
Do you want a cuppa?
没时间。
No time.
-这是紧急情况——哦。对
- This is an emergency. - Oh. Right.
好吧，深呼吸，告诉我怎么了。
Okay, well, deep breath and tell me what's up.
我不能去，但如果我不去…给人留下好印象是很重要的，你知道吗?
I can't go, but if I don't... Oh, it's so important to make a good impression, you know?
我做的事。你想给谁留下好印象?
I do. Who you trying to impress?
制片人科恩戈尔德先生。
Mr. Korngold, the producer.
我要和他一起参加Café Royal饭店的盛大晚宴。
I'm to partner him to the big dinner at the Café Royal.
——哦。-所有人都会去。
- Ooh. - Everybody will be there.
这是一个无价的机会。
It's a priceless opportunity.
但看。
But look.
哦，好吧，是有点…有点皱了，但我们可以马上把它蒸出来，亲爱的。
Oh, well, yeah, it's a bit... it's a bit crumpled, but we can steam that out in a jiffy, love.
-别担心。——不,看。
- Don't you worry. - No, look.
哦。
Oh.
哦,亲爱的。是啊，不好好泡上一段时间是洗不出来的。
Oh, dear. Yeah, that's not gonna come out without a good, long soak.
我不知道缎子会不会喜欢。
I'm not sure the satin's gonna like that.
你没有别的了吗?
Ain't you got another one?
那件漂亮的蓝色连衣裙怎么样?
What about that lovely blue dress?
-在洗衣店。——哦。
- It's at the cleaner's. - Oh.
哦,我的上帝。
Oh, my God.
我要死了。
I'm going to die.
好吧。来吧,现在。这就够了。
All right. Come on, now. That's enough.
没人想听这个。
Nobody wants to hear that.
但你不明白。
But you don't understand.
科恩戈尔德笔下几乎所有的女孩都成了明星。
Nearly all Mr. Korngold's girls become stars.
这是我摆脱陈规，最终被人看到的机会。
It's my chance to lift myself out of the rut and be seen at last.
被人看见并不代表一切，亲爱的。
Well, being seen isn't everything, love.
对我来说是。
It is for me.
来吧。站起来。
Come on. Stand up.
今天是你的幸运日。
It's your lucky day.
什么?
What?
为什么?
Why?
因为我想我能帮你。
'Cause I think I can help you.
你刚说你不能。
You just said you couldn't.
如果你不起来，我什么也做不了。
I can't do anything if you don't get up.
正确的。
Right.
脱掉你的衣服。你可以借我的裙子穿。
Take off your clothes. You can borrow my dress.
别荒谬。
Don't be ridiculous.
照我说的做，少说点废话。
Just do as I say, and a bit less of your nonsense.
到屏幕后面去。
Go on, behind the screen.
哈里斯太太吗?
Mrs. Harris?
哦。
Oh.
你们看起来很可爱，鸭子们。
You look lovely, ducks.
只是机票。
Just the ticket.
你的旅行怎么样?我应该问。
How was your trip? I should've asked.
-你去哪儿了?——哦。
- Where did you go? - Oh.
巴黎。是的,它是……你说你只会离开一天。
Paris. Yeah, it was... You said you'd only be gone a day.
没有你，一切都毁了。
Everything went to pieces without you.
这是不可思议的。
It was magical.
我是说，你知道我有多整洁…正常。
I mean, you know how tidy I am... normally.
那么浪漫。
So romantic.
太太H。
Mrs. H.
你的黑马。
You dark horse.
哦。
Oh.
哦,上帝。这是他。
Oh, God. That's him.
哦。那么，他知道到哪里来了?
Oh. He knew where to come, then?
我知道你会救我的，亲爱的。
I knew you'd rescue me, darling.
你是我的仙女教母。
You're my fairy godmother.
你好。
Hello.
彭罗斯小姐吗?
Miss Penrose?
哦。
Oh.
亲爱的H太太:这件衣服很抱歉，但请不要担心。
Dear Mrs. H, Sorry about the dress, but please don't worry.
我很好。
I'm okay.
我正对着镜子看我的口红，突然就着火了。
I was checking my lipstick in the mirror when suddenly I went up in flames.
要不是有个乐于助人的朋友来救我，我可能已经被烤焦了。
I might have burnt to a crisp if a helpful friend hadn't come to my rescue.
科恩戈尔德先生说我应该起诉。
Mr. Korngold says I should sue.
去我妈家养病了。
Gone to my mum's to recover.
艾达?
Ada?
你在吗?
You there?
是的。
Yeah.
对不起,Vi。
Sorry, Vi.
你放弃了吗，女人?
You give up the ghost, woman?
你想吓死我们吗?
You want to scare us to death?
好吧，阿奇?
Oh, all right, Archie?
抱歉弄坏了你的门。
Uh, sorry about your door.
呃，她是…最好的意图。
Uh, she was, um... Best intentions and all.
我去拿些玻璃，好吗?
I'll get some glass, yeah?
把它修好，像新的一样。
Fix it up good as new.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
好吧，一个字都不用说了。
Well, there's no need to say a word.
你是著名的。
You're famous.
至少你放弃一切去买的那条裙子是。
At least the dress you gave up everything to go and get is.
你为什么要给那个没用的女孩?
Why you give it to that no-good girl, eh?
你太软弱了，这是事实。
You're too soft, and that's the truth.
它必须被看到。
It had to be seen.
只有正确的。
It's only right.
哦,六世。
Oh, Vi.
我从来没穿过。
I never got to wear it.
甚至没有一次。
Not even once.
艾达，我亲爱的。
Oh, Ada, my darling.
我很抱歉，嗯?
I'm so sorry, eh?
嘿。
Hey.
我们不需要花哨的服装。
We don't need no fancy dresses.
我们去军团舞会上抖抖尾羽，他们都会盯着我们看。
We'll go shake our tail feather down at the Legion Dance, and they'll all be looking at us.
哦。
Aw.
哦，早上好，纽科姆先生。
Oh, morning, Mr. Newcombe.
假期愉快吗，哈里斯太太?
Enjoy your holiday, Mrs. Harris?
非常感谢。
Very much, thank you.
想念你对这个地方的触摸。
Missed your touch about the place.
哦。
Oh.
你还好吗?
Are you quite all right?
今天不太舒服。
Not quite meself today.
甚至不知道那是谁。
Not sure who that is, even.
有点生存危机。
Bit of an existential crisis.
巴黎会这样对你的。
Paris will do that to you.
别灰心，H太太。
Chin up, Mrs. H.
革命即将到来。
The revolution is coming.
你读过那个穿着迪奥礼服自焚的女孩吗?
Did you read about the girl who set fire to herself in a Dior gown?
可怕的宣传噱头，我想。
Ghastly publicity stunt, I suppose.
这是多么的浪费。
What a waste.
请接受我的通知，唐太斯夫人?
Will you please accept my notice, Lady Dant?
我要求你在这周末之前把你的账全部结清。
I will require full and final settlement of your account by the end of the week.
你不能离开我。
You can't leave me.
那种把别人当人渣对待，还指望别人忠诚的日子已经过去了。
Them days are over when you can treat people like scum and expect loyalty in return.
是的。美好的一天,夫人。
Yeah. Good day, milady.
那就这样吧。
There you go.
很快就会好的。
Be right as rain in no time.
那是谁呢?
Who's that, then?
Ada哈里斯夫人?
Mrs. Ada Harris?
-请在这里签名。——哦。
- Sign here, please. - Oh.
——谢谢。-就一会儿。有更多的。
- Thank you. - Just a mo'. There's more.
更多?
More?
哦。
Oh.
你确定吗?今天不是我的生日。
Are you sure? It's not me birthday.
你是艾达·哈里斯吗?
You are Ada Harris?
嗯，我也不确定。
Well, not sure about that, either.
Chère哈里斯夫人，我们希望您返回伦敦的旅途愉快，但我们被在社交页面上看到的一张照片所困扰。
Chère Madame Harris, We hope your return journey to London was pleasant, but we were troubled by a photo we saw in the social pages.
我们立刻意识到你又一次太仁慈了。
We knew immediately that once again you had been too kind.
你弄错了!停!
You've got it wrong! Stop!
看来垃圾大王这是个错误，我告诉你!
It seems the rubbish king It's a mistake, I'm telling you!
偷他工人的钱
Was stealing from his workers.
乔治!乔治!
Georges! Georges!
由于他的资产被查封，阿瓦隆夫人没有参加最后的试衣，也没有为她的衣服付账。
Since his assets were seized, Madame Avallon failed to attend her final fitting or settle the bill for her dress.
我们保留了你所有的测量数据，当然是85。
We kept all your measurements, of course, Eighty-five.
很快就能帮你修改了。
And were quickly able to alter it for you.
如果它需要任何最后的调整，我们知道你有能力自己做这些。
If it needs any final adjustments, we know you have the skill to do these yourself.
我们都同意这是克里斯汀·迪奥的办公室。我在听。
We all agreed it was Office of Christian Dior. I'm listening.
这是我们能做的。
The least we could do.
宣传使订单大大增加。
The publicity has resulted in a great increase in orders.
请你把这些包起来好吗?
Could you wrap these up please?
你一定会认出这些花是玛格丽特公主的喜悦。
You will no doubt recognize these blooms as Princess Margaret's Delight.
我们希望你喜欢这些花，并让你的新裙子远离明火。
We hope you enjoy the flowers and that you will keep your new dress well away from naked flames.
我们把它送给你，表达我们所有的爱和最热烈的感谢。
We send it to you with all our love and our very warmest thanks.
克里斯汀和你迪奥的朋友们送你的。
From Christian and all your friends at the House of Dior.
可爱。谢谢你！
Lovely. Thank you.
很高兴见到你。
G-Good to see you.
-再见。——好的。
- See you later. - All right.
给你，亲爱的。
There you go, love.
把它拿下来。
Get that down you.
——干杯。——干杯。
- Cheers. - Cheers.
谢谢你,Vi。
Thank you, Vi.
哦,艾达。
Oh, Ada.
阿奇，你没事吧?
You all right, Archie?
没有更好的。
Never better.
S-Sorry。
S-Sorry.
我只是…什么?
I just... What?
你看起来不同。
You seem different.
嗯，这是高级时装，你知道吗?
Well, it's haute couture, you know?
是,现在?
Is it, now?
知道吗?
Know what?
不是衣服的问题。我是说，这很可爱，但是…不,这是你。
It's not the frock. I mean, it's lovely and all, but, uh... no, it's you.
你……你只是美丽。
You... You're just beautiful.
谢谢你,阿奇。
Thank you, Archie.
你真好。
That's very nice of you.
不，我是说，你一直很漂亮。
No, I mean, you've always been beautiful.
内外。
Inside and out.
只是,有一些……我不知道，好像是新的火花之类的。
Just, there's something... I don't know, like, a new spark or something.
难以启齿?
A je ne sais quoi?
就是他了。
That'll be the fella.
我欠你一支舞，对吧?
I owe you a dance, don't I?
我想你知道。
I think you do.
我想和这房间里最可爱的女孩共舞。
I'd like to claim that dance with the loveliest girl in the room.
今天是你的幸运日。
It's your lucky day.
哦。
Oh.
好吧。
All right.
我们所有人都有希望。
There is hope for us all.